



Amosa Temitope Ibrahim

(+234) 8035331183

Email address: amosatemitopeibrahim@gmail.com

Address: 12, Aminat Akata Street, Orisunmibare Community, Okolowo, Ilorin, Nigeria.

ABOUT ME

A tech savvy graduate of computer engineering with more than 2 years of progressive hands on experience in Digital Signal Processing and Data Communication, as well as Embedded system and automation. Motivated by increasing needs for AI-based solution for industrial problems. Also, an IT enthusiast that seeks acquisition of knowledge through research findings and use of such knowledge to bridge the gap between research findings and practical application.

FORMAL EDUCATION

B.Eng in Computer Engineering (Second Class Upper Honours)

University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria [2014 – 2019]

FURTHER EDUCATION

IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate, Google - [2020]

This course focused on how to manage IT resources at scale, both for physical machines and virtual machines in the cloud, analyzes real-world IT problems and Implement the appropriate strategies to solve those problems.

Cybersecurity Compliance Framework and system Administration, IBM - [2020]

The course gives background understanding of key cybersecurity compliance and industry and industry standards.

Learn to Design Solar Systems for Residence and Indurial Use, Utra-Tech - [2020]

The course worked me through facts, calculations, how to design solar system with various installation techniques. The course also covered cost analysis of the entire solar systems.

Machine Learning, Stanford University - [2020]

This course provides a broad introduction to machine learning, data mining, and statistical pattern recognition.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Digital Signal Processing Lab, University of Ilorin, Nigeria [2020 - present]

- Assisted a professor of the department Computer Engineering in preparing notes and slides on Data Communication and Computer Networks modules, and in lecture delivery by taking tutorials and relevant lab demonstration.
- Reviewed extensive academic literature on Nanoparticle and 3D Nanofabrication
- Explored a research niche in the area of Multifunctional Nano colloids and Nanotechnology.

Research Assistant

Data Communication Lab, University of Ilorin, Nigeria [2019 – 2020]

- Reviewed extensive academic literature on Optimization Techniques for Antenna, Using Several Algorithm
- Assisted the research team in data collection by monitoring the energy meter and collecting the data daily.
- Explored a research niche in the area of Microwave Communication.

Field Engineer

Transmission Company of Nigeria, Nigeria [2019 – 2020]

- Participated in Power system design, Implementation, construction and maintenance.
- Worked with the team of engineering during the installation and maintenance of three phase Intelligent Transformer (Electroflow).



Public Health Protector Volunteer

Safe Environment Initiative [2019 – 2020]

- Collaborated with the Water Step to distribute disinfectant (bleach) across 200 Primary Health Care (PHC) centres to prevent and fight the spread of COVID-19 in Jigawa-State, Nigeria.
- Spoke on Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) to create awareness and sensitize members of the community at Community Development Service (CDS) in Jigawa-State, Nigeria.
- Visited Elementary and High schools to sensitize the students on appropriate hygiene practices like proper hand washing habits.
- o Organized clean-up events periodically in different local government of Jigawa-State, Nigeria.

Control Engineer (Intern)

Egbin Power Plc, Lagos. [Jun 2018 - Nov 2018]

- Loop-checks on various instrument and control systems
- Installation, configuration, calibration and maintenance of HART and SMART protocol valves positioner and transmitters (pressure, differential pressure, Temperature, Level, Flow etc.)
- Maintenance of Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs) instrumentation
- help in carrying-out condition monitoring of plant equipment and recorded observations as recommended by the original equipment manufacturer (OEM)

ORGANIZATIONAL/MANAGERIAL SKILLS

Leadership Skills

- Leadership :- I was the group leader of over 100 students at the Community Development Scheme (CDS) for 2017/2018 academic session.
- Class Representative from 2015 2019.
- Interpersonal Skills :- I organised tutorial sessions to help my classmates and lower-level students in difficult courses during my undergraduates studies.

Digital Skills

CAD & Simulation

Programming Languages

AutoCAD, Livewire, Proteus Design Suite, MATLAB.

Python, HTML, Java.

Other Skills

- Team Work
- Time management
- Proactive
- Entrepreneurial

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English

LISTENING: C1 READING: C1 WRITING: C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION: C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION: C1

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Seminars

- International E-Conference on COVID-19 Global Impacts, African-British Journals.
- Webinar: Canadian Solar Optimization of Bifacial PV Systems with Sting Inverters.
- International Conference and Exhibition, National Society of Black Engineers, Accra, Ghana. August, 2019.
- Nigeria Society of Engineers, Ilorin Branch: Basic Software and Hardware Development, 2019.

Publications

Weather Monitoring Design Fundamentals: Temperature and Relative Humidity as Case study,
Nigerian Journal of Technological Development (Under Review).



Awards and Honours

- Muslim Students Society of Nigeria's Award of Academic Excellence, University of Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria (2017/2018).
- Computer Engineering Student Association's Most Innovative Student Award 2019
- Muslim Corpers' Association of Nigeria's Award of Excellence, Jigawa State, Nigeria 2020.

Membership

- Member, International Association of Engineers, ID: 263689
- Graduate Member, Nigerian Society of Engineers [2019]

REFERENCES

∘ Dr. Ave Taiwo Aiibove

Senior Lecturer of Computer Engineering Department of Compputer Engineering Faculty of Engineering and Technology University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria. ajiboye.at@unilorin.edu.ng

+234 803359 8680

o Dr. Jaiyeola Femi Opadiji

Associate Professor of Computer Engineering Department of Compputer Engineering Faculty of Engineering and Technology University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria. jopadiji@unilorin.edu.ng

+234 803574 9007

o Dr. Oladimeji Ibrahim

Lecturer of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Faculty of Engineering and Technology University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria. ibrahim.o@unilorin.edu.ng

+234 806242 1820